{"data":[{"question":"When I got there he _____ for two hours.","a":"had painted","b":"had been painting","c":"has painted","d":"painted","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past ( They painted before and may continue painting after I arrived) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"Mr Smith was tired because he _____ all day.","a":"had had worked","b":"had been working","c":"worked","d":"was working","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous before another action in the past is a good way to show cause and effect: \nWorked all day- tired \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"The secretary _____ letters for two hours when he arrived.","a":"had been typing","b":"had typed","c":"was typing","d":"typed","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past ( She typed before and may countinue typing after he arrived) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"The children were tired because they _____ football all morning.","a":"played","b":"had played","c":"had been playing","d":"were playing","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous before another action in the past is a good way to show cause and effect: \n- Played all morning- tired \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"There was still a smell of cigarettes. Someone _____ there.","a":"was smoking","b":"had smoked","c":"smoked","d":"had been smoking","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous \n- Before another action in the past is a good way to show cause and effect: \n- Smoked- smell \n- Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"He _____ in those mountains for years when we met.","a":"had lived","b":"was living","c":"had been living","d":"lived","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past ( They lived there before and may continue living there after we met) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"That Greek jug _____ on the sea bed for 2,000 years.","a":"had been lying","b":"had lain","c":"had been laying","d":"had laid","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past (It lied there before and continued lying there) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"The sergeant _____ in the army for 20 years when I joined the regiment","a":"had served","b":"had been serving","c":"was serving","d":"had serviced","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past ( She served there before and my continue serving after I joined) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"They _____ old papers all morning when I saw them.","a":"had collected","b":"had been collecting","c":"collected","d":"are collecting","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past (They collected before and may countinue collecting after I saw) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"It was obvious that he _____ heavily all night. He couldn't stand up.","a":"had been drinking","b":"was drinking","c":"drank","d":"is drinking","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous\n+ Before another action in the past is a good way to show cause and effect:\nDrank heavily-> could not stand\n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"}]}